Finding Aid for wilsondoncollectiontwo
Clarke Historical Library
Don Wilson Collection 1885-2015, and undated
Wilson, Don.
11.5 cubic ft. (in 11 boxes, 3 slide boxes, 2 note card boxes of slides, 21 Oversized folder)
MSS.
The collection mostly documents Michigan railroads, focusing on the Ann Arbor Railroad Company (AARR), related lines, and its ferries in many formats. Also included are some organizational records of the Ann Arbor Railroad Technical and Historical Association (AARTHA).
Clarke Historical Library, Central Michigan University
Acc # 74460, 74499, 75617
Don Wilson Collection is open for research.
Biography:
Don Wilson (1937-2013) was a member of the Ann Arbor Railroad Technical and Historical Association (AARTHA). He was a veteran of the U.S. Army having served in Viet Nam and Thailand. He taught school for 30 years and coached several sports teams. He was also a member of the Chesaning-Brady Fire Department for 42 years. A copy of his obituary is found at the front of Box 1. The Clarke Historical Library houses several of his railroad and/or ferries collections.
The collection is organized by size and format, and then in alphabetical and chronological order.
Collection, collected over time by Don Wilson, some of which he was given by other rail fans. The collection mostly documents Michigan railroads, focusing on the Ann Arbor Railroad Company (AARR), related lines, its reorganization, abandonment, and its ferries. Some ferry information is general such as Twin Screw Specs (Box 5), and there is information specific to the M.V. [Motor Vessel] Viking (originally Ann Arbor No. 7) and the City of Milwaukee. Formats include slides, photographs, negatives, photograph printing plates, blueprints, scrapbooks, photograph albums, speeches, notes, newspaper clippings and magazine articles, maps, digital scans and positive prints from those scans, a CD, and miscellaneous, related publications. Also included are some organizational records of the AARTHA. Other railroads documented to various degrees in the collection include: Central Michigan Railroad (CM); Detroit, Caro and Sandusky Railroad (DC and S); Detroit, Toledo, and Ironton Railroad; Grand Trunk Railway (GT); Green Bay and Western Railroad; H and E Railroad [probably the Huron and Eastern]; Manistique and Lake Superior Railroad; Michigan Interstate Railway Company; Michigan Northern Railway Company; Mid-Michigan Railroad; New York Central Railroad (NYC) and St. Louis Railroad (SLRR); New York Central State Railroad (NYCS); Norfolk and Western Railway Company; Northwestern Pacific Railroad; Penn Central Railroad; Southern Pacific Transportation Company; Tuscola, Saginaw Bay Railroad (TSBRR); Toledo, Owosso, and Flint Railroad (TOandFRR); Wabash Railroad, and Wisconsin Central Railroad.
Items of special interest to researchers may include: manifests of the M.V. Viking, February-August 1976, and AARTHA bylaws, meeting minutes, newsletter information, member lists, and other information (Box 1); reorganization information (see Vincent M. Malanaphy folders (Boxes 2, 4), Michigan Interstate Railway Co. and MI Rail System Rationalization Plan information (Box 4), AARR photographs (Boxes 2-3), Pamona Derailment Negatives, undated (Box 5).
Photographs, negatives, and history of a plethora of railroad related topics are found throughout the collection. There are three slide boxes and two note card boxes full of slides on railroads (Slide Boxes 1-5).
Blueprints include line, lever circuit controllers, and station design plans, styling and painting design, system maps, tracks and structures, equipment, station and train car blueprints, and property drawings.
The 2016 addition, Boxes 14-16 and Folder #21 (legal-size), 1.5 cubic feet from Don’s friend Don Maddock was organized by Maddock into the series of Abandonment Petitions and Michigan Interstate Era. Included are paper documents, scans and positive prints of some of Wilson’s negatives, a few other topical files, a CD, and three color photographs. The addition largely documents the reorganization and end of the AARR. Sale papers for the City of Milwaukee are included. Most of the 2019 addition papers are copies. Note: 2016 addition negatives are housed in print file negative preservers, not archival negative sleeves.
Researchers may be interested in knowing that there are several collections and many publications by and about the Ann Arbor Railroad in the Clarke, as well as other collections and published sources documenting other railroad companies.
Processing Note: The collection is organized by size and format, and then in alphabetical and chronological order. A few publications, two general railroad films, and a tote bag were returned to the members of the AARTHA. Some publications (24), both monographs and parts of serials, were cataloged separately and added to the Clarke’s collections. Some of the items are quite acidic or fragile, most of which were photocopied and the originals were withdrawn from the collection (.25 cubic ft. total). In a few cases, where entire folders were composed of very fragile tissue paper records or acidic records, the decision was made to leave the materials as they were without copying them. Numerous abbreviations were used by Mr. Wilson within the collection, which were replicated by the processors. Michigan was often abbreviated MI by Mr. Wilson and is used in this finding aid. See the Scope and Contents Note for abbreviations used for names of railroad companies.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor Railroad Company--History.; Ann Arbor Railroad Company--Planning.; Ann Arbor Railroad Technical and Historical Association.; Detroit, Toledo, and Ironton Railroad--History.; Tuscola and Saginaw Bay Railway Company.; American Bureau of Shipping.; Grand Trunk Corporation.; Penn Central Transportation Company.; New York Central Railroad Company.; Manistique and Lake Superior Railroad Company.; Wisconsin Central Railroad Company (1954-1960); Wabash Railroad.; Michigan Interstate Railroad Company.; Ann Arbor No. 7 (Car ferry); City of Milwaukee (Car ferry); ConRail.; Michigan Northern Railway Company.; Norfolk and Western Rialway Company.; United States. Bankruptcy Court (Michigan: Eastern District); Michigan. Dept. of Transportation.; Michigan. Dept. of Licensing and Regulatory Affairs.; Ferries--Michigan.; Ferries--Michigan, Lake.; Ferries--Great Lakes (North America); Railroads--Michigan--History.; Railroads--Michigan--Planning.; Railroads--Abandonment--Michigan.; Railroads--History.; Railroads--United States--History.; Railroads--Employees.; Railroads--North America--Maps.; Blueprints.; Scrapbooks--Michigan.; Benzie County (Mich.)--History.; Saint Louis (Mich.)--History.; Whitmore Lake Region (Mich.)--History.; Chesaning (Mich.)--History.; Toledo (Ohio)--History.
- Don Wilson Collection.
  - Don Wilson Obituary,2013 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 18 Month Progress Report on A.A.R.R. System [Bad Copy],1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - A.A.R.R., A. and B. R. Ry., E. and S.-E.R.R., M. and N.-E.R.R. Stations,July 1899, June 1904 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - A.A.R.R., Agreement Covering Locomotive Engineers, Firemen-Helpers, Hostlers, and Outside Hostler-Helpers,September 1956 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - A.A.R.R., Agreement with D.G.R. and W. Railway Co.,February 1897 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - A.A.R.R., Articles from “The Inside Track”,undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - A.A.R.R., Boat Workers,1948, 1960, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - A.A.R.R., Carferry History (1 of 2),1915, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - A.A.R.R., Carferry History (2 of 2),1949 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - A.A.R.R., Certification Cards and Paperwork,1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - A.A.R.R., Circulars and Bulletins [VERY ACIDIC],1947 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - A.A.R.R., Clearance Cards (1 of 2),1976, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - A.A.R.R., Clearance Cards (2 of 2),1909, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - A.A.R.R., Conductors’ Train Reports,undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - A.A.R.R., Drawings,1914, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - A.A.R.R., D.S.S. and A. Railway,1943 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - A.A.R.R., History, “A.A.R.R., Fifty Years Ago”,undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - A.A.R.R., Line Abandon Blueprint, Ithaca to Alma,April 1897 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - A.A.R.R., Local and Joint Commodity Freight Tariff),1930, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - A.A.R.R., Local Time Tables, Effective June 1st (Copy),1934 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - A.A.R.R., Miscellaneous,1895, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - A.A.R.R., M.L.S.R.R., Locomotive Equipment,January 1930 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - A.A.R.R., M.L.S.R.R., Locomotive Equipment,January 1936 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - A.A.R.R., M.L.S.R.R., Locomotive Equipment,January 1963 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - A.A.R.R., Map (Copies),undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - A.A.R.R., “M.V. Viking,” Manifests,February 1976 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - A.A.R.R., “M.V. Viking,” Manifests,,March 1976 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - A.A.R.R., “M.V. Viking,” Manifests,,April 1976 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - A.A.R.R., “M.V. Viking,” Manifests,,May 1976 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - A.A.R.R., “M.V. Viking,” Manifests,,June 1976 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - A.A.R.R., “M.V. Viking,” Manifests,,July-August 1976 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - A.A.R.R., News Release,1981 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - A.A.R.R., Office of Superintendent,1960, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - A.A.R.R., Operating Manual, revised 1999,1999 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - A.A.R.R., Operating Proposal to MI Dept. of State Highways and Transportation,1976 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - A.A.R.R., Owosso Circulars,1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - A.A.R.R., Paycheck Endorsements,1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - A.A.R.R., Photographs,1938, undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - A.A.R.R., Pole Inspection Charts, Blueprints,1955 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Wilson, A.A.R.R., Preferred Stock,1893 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - A.A.R.R., Switch and Yard Check Lists,1915, 1981, undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - A.A.R.R., System Maps, Drawn 1970, updated 1975,1975 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - A.A.R.R. Technical and Historical Association (AARRTHA),undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - A.A.R.R. Technical and Historical Association, Board Meeting,1986 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - A.A.R.R. Technical and Historical Association, Board of Directors, Meeting Minutes,1992, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - A.A.R.R. Technical and Historical Association, By-Laws,1996 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - A.A.R.R. Technical and Historical Association, Calendar Index Update,2002 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - A.A.R.R. Technical and Historical Association, Income Records,1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - A.A.R.R. Technical and Historical Association, Insurance Information,undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - A.A.R.R. Technical and Historical Association, Newsletter Expenses,1988, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - A.A.R.R. Technical and Historical Association, Publications Committee,2002 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - A.A.R.R. Technical and Historical Association, Release Forms,1998 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - A.A.R.R., Seniority Lists,1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - A.A.R.R., Time Table #107, Taking Effect April 30th (Reprint),1939 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - A.A.R.R., T.N.H. Assoc. Membership List,undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - A.A.R.R., Track Diagram (Copy),undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - A.A.R.R., Train Location Reports,1961 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - A.A.R.R., Train Orders,1936, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - A.A.R.R., Train Orders, “Old and New”,1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - A.A.R.R., Train Orders, [VERY ACIDIC],August 1958 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - A.A.R.R., Train Schematic (Copies),1926-1927 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - A.A.R.R., Unassigned Empty Car Codes,1981 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - A.A.R.R., Vincent M. Malanaphy, Chairman and President,1981, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - A.A.R.R., W. Clark Durant, III, Trustee,1983 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Afternoon Yard Reports,1981 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - American Bureau of Shipping, Status of Surveys and Outstanding Recommendations,undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - [The] Ann Arbor Railroad Company,1920, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - B and B Notes,1972, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Blue Album, Photographs,1986 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Book #1, A.A.R.R., Photographs Collection (1 of 4),1895, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Book #1, A.A.R.R., Photographs Collection (2 of 4),1940, 1960s (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Book #1, A.A.R.R., Photographs Collection (3 of 4),1963, 1970s (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Book #1, A.A.R.R., Photographs Collection (4 of 4),1974, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Book #2, Photographs (1 of 3),1977, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Book #2, Photographs (2 of 3),1979, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Book #2, Photographs (3 of 3),1976, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Book #3, A.A.R.R., Photographs (1 of 3),1890-1980 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Book #3, A.A.R.R., Photographs (2 of 3),1890-1980 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Book #3, A.A.R.R., Photographs (3 of 3),1890-1980 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Book #4, A.A.R.R., Photographs (1 of 3),1890-1983 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Book #4, A.A.R.R., Photographs (2 of 3),1890-1983 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Book #4, A.A.R.R., Photographs (3 of 3),1890-1983 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Book #5, A.A.R.R., Photographs (1 of 2),1968-1980 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Book #5, A.A.R.R., Photographs (2 of 2),1968-1980 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Book #6, A.A.R.R., Photographs (1 of 2),1885-1980 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Book #6, A.A.R.R., Photographs (2 of 2),1885-1980 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Book #7, A.A.R.R., Photographs (1 of 3),1900-1987 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Book #7, A.A.R.R., Photographs (2 of 3),1900-1987 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Book #7, A.A.R.R., Photographs (3 of 3),1900-1987 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Book #8, A.A.R.R., Photographs (1 of 3),1887-1978 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Book #8, A.A.R.R., Photographs (2 of 3),1887-1978 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Book #8, A.A.R.R., Photographs (3 of 3),1887-1978 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Book #9, A.A.R.R., Photographs (1 of 3),1893-1980 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Book #9, A.A.R.R., Photographs (2 of 3),1893-1980 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Book #9, A.A.R.R., Photographs (3 of 3),1893-1980 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Caboose and Diesel Electric Locomotive Blueprints (Copies),1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Chart of Brief Forms,December 1958 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Consolidated Rail Corporation,1976, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Consolidated Rail Corporation, Freight Waybill,1981 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, General,1928, 1983, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence File (Copies of Letters),1986 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence on Saving A.A.R.R. (1 of 3),1980 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence on Saving A.A.R.R. (2 of 3),1980 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence on Saving A.A.R.R. (3 of 3),1980 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, V.M. Malanaphy,1981 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Daily Time Report Record, Wabash Railway – A.A.R.R.,1937-1938 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - D.C. and S., Railway Company, Manifests,1947 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Dick Cook Photographs of the A.A.R.R., Compiled 2000,2000 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - D.T.I. Railroad Co., Clearance Cards,1968, 1972, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - D.T.I. Railroad Co., Inventory,1980-1981, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - D.T.I. Railroad Co.,Yard List,1980-1981, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - “Former Ann Arbor Railroad Engineer kept Train Orders from His First Run in Nov. 1972”,1972 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - FRA Track Safety Standards,undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Freight Receipts,1910, 1912 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - General Duties of the Yard Clerk,undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Green Bay and Western R.R., Scrapbook,1978 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - G.T. Railway System, Clearance,1976, 1982, undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - “The History of the Ann Arbor Railroad”,May 1989 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - “The History of the Ann Arbor Railroad”, Research,1948- 1949, undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Images, Printing Plates,undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Information on the Milwaukee Area,undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Instructions for Installing Replacement Bearing Insert (1 of 2),1948 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Instructions for Installing Replacement Bearing Insert (2 of 2),1948 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Lawyer Correspondence, Provizer, Eisenberg, Lichtenstein, and Pearlman, P.C.,1982 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - “Loose,” Photographs,1970, 1982, undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - “Loose,” Slides,undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Mariners Pathfinder, “Viking”,1972-1982 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - McLouth Steel Corp., Packing List,1981 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - MI Interstate Railway Co., A.A.R.R., Agent Instructions Manual,1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - MI Interstate Railway Co., Income Statement,May 31, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - MI Rail Action Association, News Bulletin,November 1978 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - MI Rail System Rationalization Plan, Tier II, A.A.R.R. Report, MDOT,1982 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - MI Railroads and Names by Richard Miner, Jr.,October 1995 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Miscellaneous Articles (1 of 3),undated (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Miscellaneous Articles (2 of 3),1958, undated (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Miscellaneous Articles (3 of 3),undated (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Miscellaneous Business Correspondence,1913, 1982, undated (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Miscellaneous Information,1957, 1984, undated (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Miscellaneous Photographs (1 of 3),1967, 1981, undated (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Miscellaneous Photographs (2 of 3),1967, 1981, undated (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Miscellaneous Photographs (3 of 3),1967, 1981, undated (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Miscellaneous Railroad Publications (1 of 2),1967, 1981, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Railroad Publications (2 of 2),1973, 2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Railroad Scrapbook,undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Mid-MI R.R. Inc., History and Lists of Slides,after 1991 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Negatives,undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Clippings (copies), Photographs and Articles on Railroads in MI,1986, 1994, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Northwestern Pacific Railroad, Freight Waybill,August 1981 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - N.Y.C. and S.L.R.R. Co., Percentages,1904, 1911, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - N.Y.C.S., Correspondence and Notifications,1960, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Operating Instructions, 240RL Locomotive Brake Equipment, Westinghouse,February 1950 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Pamona Derailment Negatives,undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Penn Central Co., Correspondence,1969 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Photographic Negatives,undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Photographs (1 of 2),1950, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Photographs (2 of 2),1910, 1984, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Photographs, Saginaw Branch,1980, 1982, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Photographs, to Harry Harder,undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Photographs,undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Pocket Guide to Railroad Radio Frequencies,1987 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Position Paper of MI Interstate Railway Co. on Integrated Tug-Barge Proposal,1979 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Railroad Court Documents,1979 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Railroad Manuals,1968-1969, undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Rails Newsletters,March 1990-January 1991 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Red Album, Loose Photographs, unidentified,1967-1987 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Red Photograph Album, Railroad Photographs,undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - R.R. Property Purchased,1980 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Simplex 3 Column Book,1978 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Southern Pacific Trans. Co., Freight Waybill,1981 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Specifications for Twin Screw Steel Carferry for A.A.R.R. (1 of 3),1947 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Specifications for Twin Screw Steel Carferry for A.A.R.R. (2 of 3),1947 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Specifications for Twin Screw Steel Carferry for A.A.R.R. (3 of 3),1947 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Thomas Taber Files,2004 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Train Equipment and Station Blueprints,June 1914, April 1951 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Train Lines (Copies),undated (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Train Photogauvre, on board,undated (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Time Keeping Instructions for Daily Time Sheets,September 1979 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - T.S.B.R.R., A.A. Div. (1 of 3),1983-1985 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - T.S.B.R.R., A.A. Div. (2 of 3),1983-1985 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - T.S.B.R.R., A.A. Div. (3 of 3),1983-1985 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - T.S.B.R.R., A.A. Div., Book 10 (1 of 3),August 1984 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - T.S.B.R.R., A.A. Div., Book 10 (2 of 3),August 1984 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - T.S.B.R.R., A.A. Div., Book 10 (3 of 3),August 1984 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - T.S.B.R.R., Binder,1998 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - T.S.B.R.R., Binder of Photographs (1 of 2),1977, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - T.S.B.R.R., Binder of Photographs (2 of 2),1977, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - T.S.B.R.R., System Maps, MI Interstate System Maps,1985 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Twin Cities Railfan’s Guide, Minneapolis – St. Paul, Minnesota,1998 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Wabash R.R. Co., Booklet,July 1956 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Western Union Telegrams,1950, 1953, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Where to Watch Trains,1976 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - WI-Central LTD History and List of Slides for Presentation,after 1996 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - WI-Central R.R., Scrapbooks,1990, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - (Legal-Size): Ann Arbor Observer, A.A.R.R. Articles,December 1997 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - (Legal-Size): Ann Arbor Observer, A.A.R.R. Articles,March 2000 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - (Legal-Size): Ann Arbor Observer, A.A.R.R. Articles,April 2000 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - (Legal-Size): A.A. Carferry Construction, Ideas, Thoughts, Action, Joint Meet,1991 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - (Legal-Size): A.A.R.R. Correspondence (Copies),1979-1980, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - (Legal-Size): Ann Arbor R.R., Freight Car Equipment,January 1959 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - (Legal-Size): A.A.R.R., Station Records of Train Movements,1982 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - (Legal-Size): A.A.R.R., Technical and Historical Association, Income Records,1994 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - (Legal-Size): A.A.R.R., Technical and Historical Association, Show Work Order Number on Labor and Material Reports,1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - (Legal-Size): A.A. Track Chart, by L.W. Olson (Copy),1975 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - (Legal-Size): Benzie County, Michigan, Map and Pamphlet,1958 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - (Legal-Size): Dept. of Transportation Federal Railroad Administration, Locomotive Inspection and Repair Record,1974 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - (Legal-Size): Documents, James Pullen R.R. Collection,1944, 1956, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - (Legal-Size): D.T.I. Railroad, Blue-Line Prints, Engineering Dept., Dearborn, MI,1954, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - (Legal-Size): Grand Rapids article on Discovery of Three Shipwrecks,2005 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - (Legal-Size): Manistique and Lake Superior R.R., Freight Car Equipment,January 1959 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - (Legal-Size): MI Interstate Railway Co., v. MDOT, the MI Interstate Railway Co., Employee Stock Option Plan and Trust,1982 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - (Legal-Size): N.Y.C. System, Instructions Governing Out-of-Face Rail End System,1964, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - (Legal-Size): Part Prints (Copies), Adopted March 1981,March 1981 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - (Legal-Size): T.O. and F., Seniority Roster-Trainmen and Yardmen,1980, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - (Legal-Size): Wabash R.R. Co., A.A.R.R., Engine Registers, Form 1003,1957-1959 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - (Legal-Size): Waybill Listing,undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - (Slide Box 1): Ann Arbor slides (13 small slide boxes),undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - (Slide Box 1): A.A. MI R.R. slides (7 small slide boxes),undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - (Slide Box 2): A.A. MI R.R. slides (6 small slide boxes),undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - (Slide Box 2): A.A.R.R. slides (1 small slide box),undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - (Slide Box 2): Fire Dept. slides (1 small slide box),undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - (Slide Box 2): Other R.R. slides (12 small slide boxes),undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - (Slide Box 3): Other R.R. slides (7 small slide boxes),undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - (Slide Box 3): Mostly Unidentified R.R. (12 small slide boxes),undated (Box 11, Folder 2)